ANDREW MULLINS

Data Analytics Professional

Brooklyn, New York 503.860.1171 | mullinsajl@gmail.com

Profile

Young professional with passion for data analysis, an excellent academic record and real world work experience. Offers exceptional organizational abilities and a proven talent for quickly understanding complex systems. Strong statistical, analytical and technical abilities. Exceptional work ethic and team spirit.

Statistics/Analytical Skills:

Bayesian Analysis | Poisson Regression | Bootstrapping | Generalized Linear Models Multiple Regression | Multilevel Modeling | Logistic Regression | Value-Added Models

Education

BA in Mathematics, GPA 3.47 (3.67 in Major), Concentration in Statistics

St. Olaf College, Northfield, MN, May 2011

Dean's List (Spring 2010) | Earned Service and Leadership Scholarship (2007-2011)

Texas A&M University Junior Bridge (Summer 2010)

Earned place on intense and highly selective summer program (abstract algebra and real analysis).

Related Experience

ACHIEVEMENT FIRST, Brooklyn, NY, 2012 to Current

Fellow, Team Data

Plays a key role in a team of analysts overseeing collection, reporting and analysis of data from 25 K-12 schools in the Northeastern United States. Responsible for a wide variety of both research and operational tasks.

- Owned a 9-month project to overhaul and refine reporting for a ground-breaking teacher evaluation program. Created 20 unique dynamic reports that effectively summarize classroom growth for several hundred teachers at all grades and subjects.
- Investigated results of different runs of a value-added model to identify which parameters should be used. Provided guidance for interpretation of value-added results for a non-technical audience.
- Developed a data collection system to save time and ensure accuracy of high-stakes student achievement data. Interviewed potential users, learned new technology and developed policy for effective usage.

FARIBAULT PUBLIC SCHOOLS, Faribault, MN, 2011

College Student (Senior Capstone Project)

Collaborated with partner to design and execute research study to analyze the effect of two school funding initiatives on student achievement. Researched background literature, performed exploratory data analysis, developed multi-level analytical models and presented the results of the analysis to the Faribault Public School Board.

- Manipulated data received in multiple formats and structures using the R statistical programming environment. Saved countless hours by structuring the data for easy loading and distribution.
- Devised creative approach to isolate the key factors relating to student achievement, concluding with confidence that one of the funding initiatives had little impact on student success.
- Designed PowerPoint presentation and authored report that explained complex statistical results to nonmathematical audience, earning praise for clarity of presentation.

ST. OLAF COLLEGE ACADEMIC SUPPORT CENTER, Northfield, MN, 2010-2011

Math Tutor

Coached one struggling student per semester with accountability for developing their math skills via one-on-one mentoring. Assessed problems and designed customized remediation programs.

 Successes included turning a failing student into one receiving consistent passing grades, and helping another student decide to drop the class in favor of another subject.

Of Interest

Technical skills: R/SAS, Python, Microsoft Word, Excel and PowerPoint, Apple iWork, MySQL. **Volunteer:** Organized successful event to highlight Colombian human rights abuses (Lutheran World Relief).